<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gym | Ross Lawley]]></title>
  <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/categories/gym/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T16:29:54+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lawley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triathlon training]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/02/triathlon-training/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/02/triathlon-training</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow February is marching on and I feel like I've rested up for a couple of weeks after Janathon! &nbsp;But in truth I have been to the pool and to the Gym a couple of times, I've cycled on boris bikes and on static (*yawn*) bikes. &nbsp;But somehow not having the obligation to do something daily has made it feel like I've been resting! &nbsp;</p>


<p>What I have been focusing on recently is planning my training for the London Triathlon in just over 20 weeks.</p>


<p>[[posterous-content:jBwduxGyCwewhnrDhdpD]]</p>


<p>The full schedule can be seen / downloaded here: <a href="https://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;pid=explorer&amp;chrome=true&amp;srcid=0B7YRMZQuGNQxYmFjM2YwNzEtMGVhNS00MWQxLWEyZjQtMGRjOWMxZWFiOTkw&amp;hl=en" title="Tri Plan" target="_blank">Tri Plan.pdf</a>&nbsp;- based on one seen on <a href="http://www.trifuel.com/triathlon-training/Olympic-Triathlon-Training.php" title="beginner triathlon plan" target="_blank">TriFuel</a>&nbsp;but tweaked to include gym strenghting as well (more on that in a future post).</p>


<p>Today, to start my focused gym sessions I went to the gym to calculate my One Repetition Maximums. &nbsp;This is slightly embarrising as you have to calculate the absolute maximum you can lift for any given exercise. &nbsp;As that could be dangerous the safe way to calculate it involves stacking the weights on and when you can <strong>only</strong> do between 3 - 10 reps you have a weight that you can used to calculate your 1 Rep Max.</p>


<p>I must have looked a sight, throwing weights on, huffing and puffing and only doing a few sets before wondering off to the next bit of kit. Anyway for prosperity here are my 1 Rep Maximums rounded down to the nearest actual weights for my current gym routine:</p>


<ul>
<li>Squat: 45KG</li>
<li>Vertical Traction: 80KG</li>
<li>Leg Press: 95KG</li>
<li>Hammer Curl: 15KG</li>
<li>Leg Curl: 65KG</li>
<li>Push Down: 27.5KG</li>
<li>Cable Lateral Lift: 8KG</li>
</ul>


<p>The squat figure looks a little low given the leg press value, but I can always recalculate it. &nbsp;One thing I noticed is my legs (knees?) are relatively weak, so hopefully strength training will really benefit them for future runs / cycles.</p>


<ul>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 30 - Run, Gym, Run]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-30-run-gym-run/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-30-run-gym-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back to the gym for a core strength workout. Its amazing that in just 4 sessions my strength at some of the machines seems to have improved markedly. &nbsp;Probably more to do with getting use to dealing with lactic acid build up when doing weights, rather than an increase of strength but I'll take any rewards as they come!</p>


<p>The best bit about today was I ran to the Gym did a work out and then ran back - a real win as doing cardo work in the gym isn't as fun and psychologically the gym has got a whole load closer to home!</p>


<p><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><strong style="padding: 0px; margin: 0px;">Stats</strong></span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;">:</span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><br style="padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" /></span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><strong style="padding: 0px; margin: 0px;">Weights</strong></span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;">: 35 mins</span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><br style="padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" /></span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><strong style="padding: 0px; margin: 0px;">Cardo</strong></span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;">: 20 mins</span><span style="color: #444444; line-height: 20px; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif; font-size: 16px;"><strong><br /></strong></span></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 26 - Gymtastic]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-26-gymtastic/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-26-gymtastic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well it was up and at em today! &nbsp;I was in the gym for 6:30 so I could get my janathon fix in for the day. &nbsp;I still feel self conscious at the gym - hoping that will wear off as I get used to the equipment and the gym.</p>


<p>Focusing on upper body / core strength I found it a little easier this time than last!</p>


<p><strong>Stats</strong>:<br /><strong>Weights</strong>: 35 mins<br /><strong>Cardo</strong>: 5 mins (rowing to cool down)<br /><strong>Stretches</strong>: 5 (very self conscious) mins (I haven't noticed anyone else doing stretches..)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 22 - Gym will fix it]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-22-gym-will-fix-it/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-22-gym-will-fix-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well today I went to the gym for 45 minutes. &nbsp;The plan for the gym is to focus on upper body and core strength, I figure the running is good for the legs and cycling will be to! &nbsp;So after beasting myself on the weights (doing relatively small weights on the various torture machines) my arms, chest and back are now tender (read f'ing hurt). &nbsp;So much so&nbsp;I'm really glad I have power steering, as I could really feel it straight after on the drive home! &nbsp;I'm hoping this is a newbie thing and that I will soon get used to doing weights and be able to lift weights that someone my size should be able to!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 20 - Commute and Gym]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-20-commute-and-gym/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2011/01/day-20-commute-and-gym</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, I can use the gym, I'm paying for! &nbsp;After signing up and paying on MondayI was told I had to do an induction before being allowed to use the gym. &nbsp;Well, I went last night and after being wieghed, measured; height, blood pressure and pulse: 14st 10lb, 193cm, 83/130, 48 bpm. &nbsp;I told them I had used the gym before and after being tested I could use a machine, they said I was free to use the gym! So I spent 30 mins doing some weights and finished off with a 5 minute row.</p>


<p>If anyone has any good advice on resources for planning a core strength workout - let me know! &nbsp;Its my main area of focus for the gym in prep for my first Olympic triathlon in July!</p>


<p>The commute was good, did my fastest time to kings cross in the evening! &nbsp;However, I did see on cyclist take out a young lady who stepped out into the cycling lane at a traffic lights without looking - note to self cycle defensively!</p>


<p><strong>Stats (Bike Totals):</strong></p>


<p>Distance: 3.4 mi&nbsp;</p>


<p>Duration: 00:24:06</p>


<p>Avg. Pace: 7:04min/mi</p>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
