<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: resolutions | Ross Lawley]]></title>
  <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/categories/resolutions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T16:43:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lawley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2010 resolutions and predictions]]></title>
    <link href="http://rosslawley.co.uk/2009/12/resolutions-and-predictions.html/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rosslawley.co.uk/2009/12/resolutions-and-predictions.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Resolutions</h2>


<p>Blog and blog often.   I work on some cool and varied technologies and software at <a href="http://thisisglobal.com/">Global Radio</a>.  As I've learnt loads from leading a team of python developers, writing and supporting a CMS and its ecosystem of software for our various radio websites, its high time I shared and reflected on those learnings.</p>


<p>So to kickstart my return to blogging, I've been telling various members of the family about what will be popular in the coming year - so here are my predictions for the coming year...</p>


<p><a name="more"></a><h2>Predictions for 2010</h2><p></p><ul>
<li>The rise of 3D.  Avatar has kick started a 3D revolution and now it will move towards to the mainstream, with 3d TV's sports channels, it will&nbsp;detract&nbsp;and confuse the TV market with HD and HD Ready TV's, Digital Freeview etc.. &nbsp;Looking forward to it - I loved Avatar in 3D.</li>
<li>Tablets rise and netbooks fall.  Netbooks popularity has been amazing but I think 2010 will see the netbooks wain and Tablets will be the gain popularity.</li>
<li>Android the OS of choice.  Android will continue to rise in popularity and will move / merge across to netbooks, tablets and PC's, which swiftly moves to my last prediction;</li>
<li>Chrome OS takes on Ubuntu.  Ubuntu has broken into the mainstream and helped fuel the success of netbooks, now Googles' muscle will push into the market and possibly take some market share from Windows..</li>
</ul><p></p><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img class="posterous_download_image" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7305662280706773984-3099944896271931410?l=www.rosslawley.co.uk" height="1" alt="" width="1" /></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
